生活大爆炸
第四季第三集
All right, I'm ready for my next question.
好的  我准备好答下道题目了
In a world where rhinoceroses are domesticated pets,
在一个犀牛被当宠物养的世界中
who wins the Second World War?
谁将赢得第二次世界大战
Uganda.
乌干达
Defend.
理由
Kenya rises to power on the export of rhinoceroses.
肯尼亚会因出口犀牛而崛起
A Central African power block is formed,
在中非成为一个强大的政权
colonizing North Africa and Europe.
并殖民统治北非和欧洲
When war breaks out, no one can afford the luxury of a rhino.
战争爆发后  谁也负担不起养犀牛的这份奢侈
Kenya withers, Uganda triumphs.
肯尼亚衰落  乌干达雄起
Correct.
回答正确
My turn.
轮到我了
In a world where a piano is a weapon, not a musical instrument,
在一个钢琴被当做武器而不是乐器的世界中
on what does Scott Joplin play "The Maple Leaf Rag"?
斯科特·乔普林会用什么来演奏《枫叶爵士》
（美国黑人作曲家及钢琴家）
Tuned bayonets.
调谐刺刀
Defend.
理由
Isn't it obvious?
理由不是显而易见吗
You're right. My apologies.
你说得对  我的错
What the hell are you guys playing?
你们俩在玩什么鬼游戏呢
It's a game we invented.
这是我们发明的一个游戏
It's called Counterfactuals.
我们称它为"反事实游戏"
We postulate an alternate world that differs from ours
我们假定一个在某关键方面不同于这里的世界
in one key aspect and then pose questions to each other.
然后互相就此发问
It's fun for ages eight to 80.
本游戏适合8至80岁人士
Join us.
一起来玩吧
All right.
好吧
I like a good brainteaser.
我也喜欢脑筋急转弯
Give it a whirl.
我来试试吧
You're in luck, this is an easy one.
你走运了  这道简单
In a world where mankind is ruled by a giant intelligent beaver,
在一个人类被高智商巨形海狸统治的世界中
what food is no longer consumed?
哪种食物再也吃不到了
Uh... a BLT where the "B" stands for beaver?
BLT[培根生菜番茄三明治]吗  其中B代表海狸
I don't know.
我也说不准
Leonard, be serious.
莱纳德  认真点
We're playing a game here.
我们在玩游戏呢
I can figure this out. Let's see.
我能答出来的  让我想想
Um, well, beavers eat tree bark.
海狸以树皮喂食
The only tree bark I know that humans consume is cinnamon.
我唯一了解的人类用得着树皮的食物是肉桂
So, I'll say cinnamon.
所以我说是肉桂
Incorrect.
错误
Obviously, the answer is cheese Danish.
答案很明显是芝士丹麦酥
What?
你说啥
In a world ruled by a giant beaver,
在一个被巨形海狸统治的世界中
mankind builds many dams to please the beaver overlord.
人类为取悦海狸的统治会修建许多水坝
The low-lying city of Copenhagen is flooded.
哥本哈根因地势低洼会遭遇洪灾
Thousands die.
数万人会死去
Devastated, the Danes never invent their namesake pastry.
更毁灭的是  丹麦人却从未以自己的名字给糕点命名
How does one miss that?
怎么会有人连这个都想不到呢
This is ridiculous.
这太荒谬了
You're just making stuff up.
你们这是在捏造答案
Is he always like this when he loses?
他输的时候总这样吗
Oh, yes.
那当然了
You should've been here for the great giant tantrum of 2008.
你要是能目睹08年讨论巨形野牛时的景象就好了
You bumped the table and you know it.
你掀的桌子  自己清楚
Perhaps it would be kinder to play a game more suited to his abilities.
或许我们应该玩个更适合他能力的游戏
We'll close our eyes and count to ten while you hide.
等会儿你躲猫猫的时候  我们会闭眼数到10
I'm going to my room.
我回屋了
Very good, Leonard.
很好  莱纳德
But next time, don't tell us where you're hiding.
但下次你藏哪里无需提前告诉我们
Did you guys see the paper in The American Physics Journal on supersolids?
你们看到《美国物理学报》关于超固体的论文了吗
It's pretty interesting.
挺有趣的
This guy's working from a hypothesis where...
这个人从假说...
Spoiler alert! Spoiler alert.
剧透警报  剧透警报
- What?  - Don't ruin it for me, man.
-咋了  -别提前爆料
I printed out a PDF to read on the potty.
我为了边蹲便壶边看把PDF文件都打出来了
On the potty? What are you, five?
便壶  你多大了  五岁吗
It's a potty. What do you call it?
就是便便的地方嘛  不然你说该叫什么
Toilet.
厕所
That's a little vulgar for the dinner table, don't you think?
晚饭桌上这么叫不觉得有点粗俗了吗
Oh, and "potty" is okay?
那"便壶"就不俗了吗
"Potty" is innocent. "Potty" is adorable.
"便壶"多纯真  多可爱啊
What do you do in the potty, wee-wee?
那你去便便的地方干啥  嘘嘘吗
If I don't have to boom-boom.
如果我不必"嘣嘣"[大便]的话
Greetings.
各位好
You all remember Amy Farrah Fowler.
你们都记得艾米·菲拉·福勒吧
- Nice to see you.  - Hello.
-见到你很高兴  -你好
Sorry we're late.
抱歉我们迟到了
I must take responsibility.
对此我必须得承担责任
I had to stop for feminine hygiene supplies.
我不得不半路上买点女性卫生用品
- Aha.  - Okay.
-这样啊  -了解
I believe she's experiencing her menses.
我认为她正在经期当中
Actually, I'm not.
实际上  还没到时候
In order to avoid surprises, I wear them all the time.
但为了避免意外  我得时刻带着卫生巾
- Aha.  - Okay.
-理解  -非常了解
"Toilet's" sounding pretty good now, huh?
厕所现在听起来顺耳多了是吧
Hey, look, it's Shamy.
瞧啊  这不是谢米嘛
Shamy?
谢米
A juvenile amalgamation of our names.
一个幼稚地混合我们名字的做法而已
Sheldon, Amy-- Shamy.
谢尔顿  艾米  "谢米"
Oh.
这样啊
I don't like that. Don't do that.
我不喜欢  以后别这么叫了
All righty. What's new?
好吧  有什么新鲜事吗
Well, just recently, I learned that you refer to us as Shamy,
我刚才得知你称呼我们为"谢米"
and I don't like that.
而我并不喜欢
I got it. But what I was going for was, you know, how's your life?
我了解了  但我想问的其实是你生活上的新鲜事
Like everybody else's.
跟普通人没什么两样
Subject to entropy, decay and eventual death.
经历着万物的成长  衰败和最终的死亡
Thank you for asking.
谢谢你的问候
Why is she not taking our order?
为何她还没有给我们点餐呢
I should've warned you,
我应该提前通知你的
one has to navigate a labyrinth of social nonsense
如果想在这里用餐前  必须要经历连串
before one can be fed here.
繁杂而无用的寒暄
Really? I assumed an establishment called
是吗  我以为既然起名叫芝士"工厂"
the Cheesecake Factory would function more efficiently.
做事就能更有效率呢
It's how they lure you in.
那是它们诱骗你来的伎俩
I believe it's called "bait and switch."
我想这应该称为"诱饵推销法"
Okay, I'm just gonna walk away,
好吧  我还是遁走好了
'cause... I don't want to be here.
因为  我不想待在这了
So, this is nice.
这真不错啊
First time we've all gotten together to eat.
我们第一次齐聚一堂来吃顿饭
You're right, he's a festival of humdrum chitchat.
你说得对  他果然在进行无聊的饭前寒暄
Okay, that's all I got.
好吧  我没辙了
Howard, you're up.
霍华德  你上
Um... tell us about your work, Amy.
谈谈你的工作吧  艾米
I doubt you'd understand.
我怀疑你听不听得懂
Sheldon tells me you only have a master's degree.
谢尔顿告诉我你只有个硕士学位
Raj, do you have any questions for Amy?
拉杰  你有没有问题问艾米
I'm curious as to why we're not eating alone.
我很好奇  我们怎么不单独吃饭
They can't function without me.
他们离不开我
I'm the social glue that holds this little group together.
我是凝聚这个小团体的粘合剂
You're welcome.
不用谢我
Listen, can I talk to you about your girlfriend?
我能跟你谈谈你的女朋友吗
She's not my girlfriend.
她不是我的女朋友
She's a girl and she's my friend,
她是女生  也是我朋友
but there's no touching or unsanitary exchange of saliva.
但绝对没有触摸或不洁的交换唾液
Got it.
明白
Although, for the record, on one occasion,
不过  倒是有一次
she licked her thumb to remove raspberry jelly
她舔了一下拇指  然后帮我抹掉
from the corner of my mouth.
嘴角上的树莓果冻
It's an action we both regret to this day.
我们今天都为此后悔不已
Uh-huh.
明白
Anyway, I'm not sure she's the best fit
不过  我觉得她不太适合
for our little-- how should we call it-- rebel alliance.
我们这个  怎么说呢  反抗军[星球大战]
Oh, I never identified with the rebel alliance.
我一直不认同反抗军
Despite their tendency to build Death Stars,
尽管他们想建造死亡星球
I've always been more of an empire man.
我一直支持银河帝国
Yeah, not my point.
那不是我想说的
I know what your point is.
我知道你想说什么
You're intimidated by Amy's intellect.
你们被艾米的智慧吓着了
To that I say, buck up.
我只能说  振作点
Okay, let me just get right to it.
我直接说吧
Amy is judgmental, sanctimonious and frankly...
艾米很爱批评人  假正经  而且
just obnoxious.
很讨人厌
So?
那又如何
So we already have you for all that.
我们已经要忍受这样一个你了
Are you suggesting I terminate my relationship with Amy?
你这是建议我停止和艾米交往吗
No, no, of course not.
不  当然不是
Just have your relationship someplace else.
只是去别的地方交往
May I point out that for eight long months,
那我可得指出  我忍气吞声整整八个月
I suffered in silence as your female companion
忍受你女朋友在咱家
filled our apartment with her off-key country music caterwauling,
大声唱跑调的乡村音乐
the unappetizing spectacle of her grinding a pumice stone
毫不知羞地在咱客厅
against her calloused feet in our living room,
用浮石磨长满老茧的脚
and night after night of uninformative
一夜接一夜地看
TV documentaries about the Jersey Shore.
毫无内涵的电视剧《泽西海滩》
Suffered in silence?
忍气吞声
Yes.
没错
And I'd thank you to do the same.
我希望你也能这么做
Reall-- Silence?!
有没有搞错  忍气吞声
Nothing makes beer taste better
落基山脉清凉的泉水
than cool clear Rocky Mountain spring water.
最能带出啤酒的味道
Where are the Rocky Mountains, anyway?
话说  落基山脉在哪啊
Philadelphia.
费城[实际不是]
Really?
真的吗
I thought they were out West someplace.
我以为在西部呢
Think about it, Raj.
这样想  拉杰
Where did the movie Rocky take place?
电影《洛奇》的故事发生在哪里
Philadelphia.
费城
Okay, now I get it.
我明白了
So this is the plan?
这就是咱的计划吗
From now on,
从今天起
we're just gonna hide out in here to avoid the Shamy?
我们就藏这里躲避谢米吗
I'm very comfortable here.
我觉得这里很舒服
Penny, dear, why don't you shoot another silver bullet my way?
佩妮亲爱的  再给我来一剂"万灵弹"吧
Get one yourself.
自己拿去
Ooh, somebody's been taking bitchy pills.
某人吃了泼妇药哦
God, he's an ass when he drinks.
老天  他喝了酒真混蛋
Oh, he's an ass when he doesn't.
他没喝酒也混蛋
You just don't hear it.
你只是没听到
Think we need to start entertaining the possibility
我们得考虑谢米恋
that the Shamy could go on for years.
发展数年的可能性
Well, if that's the case, Penny will have to get satellite TV
那样的话  佩妮得装卫星电视
and maybe once a week run a vacuum through this place.
而且每周吸一吸灰尘
I thought you were going to talk to Sheldon.
你不是要跟谢尔顿谈吗
- I did.  - Well, what'd he say?
-谈了  -他怎么说
Well, he pointed out that he kinda sorta had to...
他指出他过去有点必须
put up with you.
忍受你
Kinda sorta had to?
有点必须
I didn't agree with him.
我没同意他的说法
Well, you defended me, right?
你帮我反驳了吧
I tried, but...
我试了  不过
...he made a fairly well-reasoned argument.
他说的理由太充分了
You're not doing that right.
你磨得不对
What?
什么
Gimme.
给我
- No.  - Trust me.
-不要  -相信我
- No!  - I do this for my mom all the time.
-不要  -我一直帮我妈磨脚
See?
看到没
With the grain.
要顺着纹路摩
Wow, that is better.
哇  确实好很多
And someday, when you have varicose veins,
改天  你要是得了静脉曲张
I'll show you how to massage them.
我再教你怎么推拿
Oh, God, never again.
天呐  没有下次了
I assume by "never again," you mean never again will you drink
你的"没有下次"应该是指不再
all of Penny's beer, then run down to the gas station
喝完佩妮的啤酒后跑去加油站
for a couple of 40s, a box of Slim Jims
买两瓶40s啤酒  一盒肉条
and the latest issue of Bombay Badonkadonks.
还有最新一期的《孟买美妞翘臀》吧
I was homesick.
人家想家了嘛
The highlight of the evening was when you showed us
当晚最精彩的就是你展示
your Bollywood break dancing skills.
你的宝莱坞霹雳舞技
That's very offensive.
你这样很没礼貌
Yeah, we all thought so.
没错  我们当时也这么想
Oh, no.
晕
What?
怎么了
It's John and Yoko.
约翰和洋子来了[列侬夫妇]
More like Yoko and Yoko.
更像洋子和洋子
Greetings. Hey.
大家好
I brought Amy here
我带了艾米来
to show her some of the work I'm doing.
看看我的工作
It's very impressive, for theoretical work.
对于理论工作来说  很不错了
Do I detect a hint of condescension?
我好像察觉出一点屈就的意味
I'm sorry, was I being too subtle?
抱歉  我说得太间接了吗
I meant compared to the real-world applications
我是指跟神经生物学
of neurobiology, theoretical physics is--
在现实中的应用相比  理论物理就是
what's the word I'm looking for?-- hmm, cute.
怎么说好呢  小巫见大巫
Are you suggesting the work of a neurobiologist
你这是暗指神经生物学家的成就
like Babinski could ever rise to the significance
例如巴宾斯基  能上升到物理学家
（巴宾斯基  法国神经学家）
of a physicist like Clark Maxwell or Dirac?
例如克拉克·麦克斯韦或狄拉克的层面
（克拉克·麦克斯韦：经典电动力学创始人  狄拉克：量子力学奠基者之一）
I'm stating it outright.
直截了当地说
Babinski eats Dirac for breakfast
巴宾斯基把狄拉克当早餐
and defecates Clarke-Maxwell.
再排泄出克拉克·麦克斯韦
You take that back.
你给我收回那话
Absolutely not.
绝不
My colleagues and I are mapping
我和同事们正在绘制
the neurological substrates that subserve
神经基质  有利于
global information processing,
促进全球信息处理
which is required for all cognitive reasoning,
这种研究既要求认知推理
including scientific inquiry, making my research ipso facto
也包括科学探索  由此事实可见
prior in the ordo cognoscendi.
我的研究在认知序列上更高一层
That means it's better than his research,
这就说明比他的研究更高级
and by extension, of course, yours.
由此可推  当然也胜过你们
I'm sorry, I'm-I'm still trying
不好意思  我的大脑
to work on the defecating Clark Maxwell, so...
还停留在理解排泄克拉克·麦克斯韦上
Excuse me, but a grand unified theory,
不好意思  但是统一场理论
insofar as it explains everything,
在一定程度上解释了万物
will ipso facto explain neurobiology.
由此事实可见  也能解释神经生物学
Yes, but if I'm successful,
是没错  但要是我成功了
I will be able to map and reproduce your thought processes
我就能绘制和再现你演算出
in deriving a grand unified theory,
统一场理论的思维加工过程
and therefore, subsume your conclusions under my paradigm.
因此  你的结论也得纳入我的范式
That's the rankest psychologism,
那是卑劣的心理主义
and was conclusively revealed as hogwash
早在19世纪90年代就被费雷格
by Gottlob Frege in the 1890s!
板上钉钉为是胡言乱语
We appear to have reached an impasse.
看来我们陷入了僵局
I agree.
同意
I move our relationship terminate immediately.
我决定立即终止我俩的关系
Seconded.
赞同
There being no objections...
还有异议吗
...the motion carries.
那么立即执行
Good day, Amy Farrah Fowler.
日安  艾米·菲拉·福勒
Good day, Sheldon Cooper.
日安  谢尔顿·库珀
Women, huh?
女人哈
Can't live with them,
没法和她们过日子
can't successfully refute their hypotheses.
也没法反驳她们的各种假设
Amen to that.
上帝保佑
Hey, Sheldon.
好呀  谢尔顿
Hello.
你好
I hear you broke up with Amy.
听说你和艾米分手了
A breakup would imply she was my girlfriend.
说"分手"的话就说明她是我女朋友
She was a girl who was my friend
她是个女孩  曾经是我朋友
who is now a girl who is not my friend.
现在她还是个女孩  但不是我朋友了
Wow. That's like the worst country song ever.
听着像史上最烂乡村民谣
So, how are you doing?
你感觉如何
Regarding what?
什么感觉
Amy.
和艾米分手
I don't follow.
我不懂
Well, breakups-- or whatever the hell this is-- can be tough.
分手...不管你怎么叫  总是很难受的
Penny, I assure you, I'm fine.
佩妮  放心  我没事
My relationship with Amy was purely intellectual,
我和艾米只是纯粹智力上的关系
There were no emotional bonds,
没有丝毫感情色彩
the severing of which would cause me any discomfort.
所以我也没有任何痛苦
The relationship simply outlived its utility,
这段关系只是失去效用罢了
and I'm continuing on with my life as before.
我也像从前一样继续生活
Okay. Good.
好吧  不错
Now, if you'll excuse me, I'm off to buy a pussycat.
我得先走了  要去买一只小猫咪
I gotta tell you guys,
这事儿必须跟你们说一下
I'm a little worried about Sheldon.
我有点担心谢尔顿
We're all a little worried about Sheldon.
我们都有点担心谢尔顿
No, I mean since the Shamy hit a reef.
我是说自从谢米恋搁浅后
Oh, I thought you were just making a generalization:
我还以为你是一概而论呢
"You know, I'm worried about Sheldon
"我担心谢尔顿  可能他某天"
"someday setting off a low-yield nuclear device
会因为在咖啡馆吃不到酸橙果冻
because the cafeteria ran out of lime Jell-O."
就去引爆一个低爆炸力核装置
What does "hit a reef" mean?
搁浅是啥意思
Uh, went splitsville.
一拍两散
Pardon?
啥
Turned to boom-boom.
就是"屎了"
I think Sheldon really misses Amy.
我觉得谢尔顿真的很想念艾米
You should lend him your copy of Bombay Badonkadonks.
你该把你的那本《孟买美妞翘臀》借给他
He got a cat to keep him company.
他找了只猫作伴
You're kidding.
不是吧
He takes it everywhere:
他上哪儿都带着
to bed, to the bathroom.
不管是卧室还是洗手间
He takes the kitty to the potty?
他带猫咪用便壶吗
I thought we discussed the P-word.
我们不是说好不用这词儿了么
Don't try to change me, dude.
别想着改变我  老兄
I am what I am.
哥就是哥
Oh, gentlemen.
先生们
Hey. Aren't you going to introduce us
不给我们介绍下
to your little friend?
你的小伙伴吗
My apologies.
不好意思
Raj, Howard, I'd like you to meet Dr. Robert Oppenheimer.
拉杰  霍华德  这位是罗伯特·奥本海默博士
Hello. Hi.
你好
Now, if you'll excuse me,
失陪一下
the father of the atomic bomb wants a saucer of milk.
原子弹之父现在要来一碟牛奶
Okay, I get it. We're worried about Sheldon.
我懂了  的确该担心谢尔顿
Yeah.
是吧
Hey.
回来了
Oh, no.
不是吧
Robert Oppenheimer was lonely.
奥本海默太孤单了
So you decided to get the whole Manhattan Project?
所以你要把整个曼哈顿计划的人都找来吗
（美国制造原子弹计划的代号）
Yes. This is Enrico Fermi, Richard Feynman,
对  这位是恩里科·费米  理查德·费曼
Edward Teller,
爱德华·泰勒
Otto Frisch
奥托·弗里希
and Zazzles.
还有犀利哥
Zazzles?
什么鬼名字
I was going to name him Hermann von Helmholtz,
我本想给他取名为赫尔曼·冯·赫尔姆霍兹
but he's so zazzy.
但他实在太犀利了
Okay, we need to talk.
好吧  我们得谈谈
About what?
谈什么
Cats, Sheldon.
猫呗  谢尔顿
You're clearly upset about Amy being gone,
显然艾米走后  你很难受
and you're trying to replace her with a bunch of cats.
所以你想用一堆猫来代替她
- Clowder. - What?
-一群猫  -啥
A group of cats is a clowder. Or a glaring.
不用一堆  而要用一群  或者是一窝子
Okay, yeah, fine.
好吧  我懂了
It's the kind of thing you ought to know
既然我们现在与猫为伍
now that we have one.
我觉得有必要给你扫盲一下
Terrific. My point is, you need to face up
很好很强大  我的意思是
to what you're feeling with this breakup.
你得坦然面对这次分手
It wasn't a breakup.
这不是分手
A breakup would imply that Amy was my girlfriend.
那样的话就说明她是我女朋友
Okay, I got it, I got it; she's not your girlfriend.
好吧  我知道了  她不是你女朋友
Now listen to me.
听我说
I know about loneliness.
我知道孤单一人的感觉
I know about trying to replace someone with other stuff.
也明白要借其它事物来寻求安慰
When I broke up with Penny, I got back into my cello,
我那会和佩妮分手后  我又重新开始拉大提琴
I built a bunch of model rockets,
还搭了不少模型火箭
I got those weightlifting gloves and that five-pound dumbbell.
我还买了举重手套和五磅重的哑铃
You didn't break up, she dumped you.
你那不叫分手  是佩妮甩了你
She didn't dump me.
她才没甩了我
It was mutual!
这是互相的
I was there. She dumped you.
我就在场  是她甩了你
Okay, fine.
好吧  随你吧
Live with cats.
跟猫一起住吧
Be like my Aunt Nancy.
跟我南希姨妈一样
She had dozens of them.
她就跟几十只猫一起住
And do you know what happened after she died? They ate her.
你知道她死后怎么样了吗  猫把她给吃了
You don't have to sell me on cats, Leonard.
不用再跟说服我喜欢猫了  莱纳德
I'm already a fan.
我已经喜欢了
（Fancy Feast[珍喜]：普瑞纳公司出的猫粮罐头）
All right, fellas, who's in the mood for Fancy Feast?
好了小家伙们  谁想来吃点珍喜猫罐头
Well, that's not fancy at all.
这可一点都不喜人
Hi, Mrs. Cooper. Thanks for coming.
你好  库珀夫人  谢谢你赶来
Where is he?
他人呢
He's in his bedroom.
在他卧室
Now, when you said on the phone
你在电话里说的
he broke up with a girl, you meant an actual girl,
他跟个女孩分手了  是指真的女孩吧
not something you kids whipped up in a lab?
不是什么你们在实验室造出来的那种
No, she's real.
不  是真的人
Did they sin?
他们做了违反教规的事吗
No, no, it's not like that.
不  不是那样的
It's, uh...
是...
I don't know what it's like.
我不知道怎么描述
But there is something I should prepare you for.
但有些事  请你作好心理准备
Oh, relax, Leonard, I have raised that boy.
放心吧莱纳德  他是我一手拉扯大的
I've seen him at his best, I've seen him at his worst.
最好的我见过  最坏的我也见过
There's nothing he can do that'll surprise me.
没什么能让我吃惊的了
Hold on to that thought.
话别说这么早
Come in.
请进
Surprise.
吃惊吧
Mom, what an unexpected pleasure.
妈  真是意外之喜
My, my, that's a powerful smell.
天  好大一股味
I'd like you to meet Oppenheimer, Frisch, Panofsky,
向你引见奥本海默  弗里希  潘诺夫斯基
Feynman, Weisskopf...
费曼  维斯可夫
Yeah, I get it.
好了  我明白了
You got a lot of cats
你养了很多猫
and you gave 'em cute Jewish names.
还给它们起了可爱的犹太名字
What are you doing here?
你来这干嘛
Leonard called.
莱纳德打电话给我的
And he said that you were pining for a young lady.
他说你为伊人消得人憔悴
Oh, that's preposterous.
那太可笑了
I'm not pining over anyone.
我才没有为谁憔悴
Oh, lambchop, we can quibble what to call it,
哦小羊排  我的说法或许不合适
but I think we can both agree it's creepy.
但我们都同意  这事儿让人毛骨悚然
I do not agree.
我才不同意
Cats make wonderful companions.
猫是很好的伙伴
They don't argue or question my intellectual authority,
不会跟你吵  也不会质疑你的才智权威
and this little guy here,
还有这个小家伙
I think you'll find to be quite zazzy.
你们会发现它实在太犀利了
You should have called sooner.
你真该早点打给我的
Shelly! Dinner's ready!
谢利  吃饭了
Coming!
来了
No cats!
不许带猫
What is she doing here?
她来这干嘛
I called her.
我打给她的
Your mother thinks
你妈妈认为
you might be losing your mind over me.
你可能正因我失魂落魄
As a neurobiologist, I was curious.
作为神经生物学家  我很好奇
Well, rest assured, I am in full possession of my faculties.
放心  我心智完全正常
25 cats!
25只猫
Oh, God bless you, dear.
上帝保佑你  亲爱的
Sheldon, sit down. Let's talk.
谢尔顿  坐下  我们谈谈
All right, but you're not fooling me.
好吧  但不许骗我
Whenever you say we have to talk,
每次你说我们谈谈
it means you want me to listen.
都只许你说我听
Then stop talking.
那就闭嘴
Yes, ma'am.
是  长官
Now, the reason I called Amy over was
我找艾米过来的原因
to find out what type of person she is.
是想看看她是哪种人
And after chatting a bit,
跟她聊了一会后
I have to say that while she is a
我不得不说  虽然她是个
perfectly unique young woman,
绝对  特殊的女士
you two are definitely not suited for each other.
你们俩完全不适合对方
That's a peculiar conclusion.
这结论真奇怪
By any standard, Amy is more similar to me
不管以任何标准来衡量  艾米都比我认识的任何人
than anyone I've ever met.
跟我更像
Oh, I'm sorry, Shelly, I can't see it.
抱歉谢利  我看不出来
Well, whether you see it or not is irrelevant.
你看不看得出来没关系
I can't see subatomic particles,
我也看不到亚原子粒子
but nevertheless, they're there.
但不论任何  它们就是存在的
Excellent point.
绝妙的观点
A physics point.
且是物理学观点
Touche
讲得好
Well, putting aside the pig Latin,
别卖弄拉丁话了
it's a good thing that
很高兴看到
you two decided to end the relationship
你们决定分手
so I didn't have to end it for you.
就省得我来拆散你们了
Amy, after consideration,
艾米  再三考虑之后
I believe we may have acted rashly.
我觉得我们可能决定得太草率了
I propose we resume our relationship
我建议我们重新开始
and attempt to resolve our differences.
并尝试解决双方差异的障碍
I'll agree to that only if you'll stipulate
除非你认可  我俩之间
that 80% of our difficulties were caused by you.
80%的障碍都是你造成的
- I'll go as high as 40. - Sixty-five.
-我只认可占40%  -你占65%
Done.
成交
You understand that moving forward,
你明白我们继续的话
we deal with the fact that my mother does not approve of you?
我们得面对我妈并不认可你的现实
I do. I find being cast
我明白  我发现扮演个
in the role of bad girl oddly titillating.
坏女孩的角色  竟让我很兴奋
Would you like to see my cats?
想看看我的猫吗
I would. I love cats.
想  我喜欢猫
They're the epitome of indifference.
它们是独善其身的典范
Ah, then you may find Zazzles a little cloying.
你会发现犀利哥有点烦人
I saw what you did there.
我可算看出来了
He thinks he's such a smarty pants.
他一向自以为聪明
He's no different from any man.
其实跟其他人没什么不同
You tell 'em not to do something,
你让他们别去做什么
certainly that's all  they want to do.
他们就想做什么
If I hadn't told my brother Stumpy
要不是我让我弟弟矮胖墩
not to clear out the wood chipper by hand,
别用手去清理碎木机
we'd still be calling him Edward.
他就不会有这外号  还是爱德华了
Now, don't you move.
还有  你坐着别动
I'll bring over all the food.
我来把菜搬过来
No, no, no, I can do it.
不不不  我来就行
Well, isn't that sweet?
真是太给力了
Thank you, Amy.
谢谢你  艾米
Here's your cat.
给  你的猫
And here's your $20.
还有你的20美元
Next!
下一个
Thank you, Amy.
谢谢你  艾米
Here's your cat.
给你你的猫
And here's your $20.
还有你的20美元
Next.
下一个